Idris Shaaba

Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria



idrismusa004@gmail.com



08133180881



linkedin.com/in/idris-shaaba

Summary

Hello I'm Idris Shaaba, I'm a final year Software Engineering Student. I enjoy coding and building websites, web apps and UI/UX designs, I have also worked on a few group projects at school.

I love working to build solutions to problems I encounter.

Experience

Chief Executive Officer

Nile Startup Campus Sep 2023 - Present (2 months)

Design Lead

Google Developer Student Clubs Nile University of Nigeria Aug 2023 - Present (3 months)

User Support Intern

Nigerian Communications Commission Jul 2023 - Sep 2023 (3 months)

Network Field Engineer Intern

Galaxy Backbone
Jul 2022 - Sep 2022 (3 months)

Beta Tester

WithMe

Sep 2021 - Jan 2022 (5 months)

During my time as a beta tester for WithMe, I had the opportunity to test and explore the app's social and gaming features. I customized my unique look and connected with friends who brought out the best in me. I also tested the app's creative features by experimenting with the drawing boards and showing off my style. Throughout my testing process, I made sure to follow the app's requirements and use it in an optimal environment. I identified and reported any bugs or issues that I encountered and provided feedback to help improve the app's functionality and user experience. Overall, my experience as a beta tester for WithMe was rewarding, and I enjoyed being a part of the development process.

Education

Nile University of Nigeria

Bachelor of Science - BS, Software Engineering 2020 - 2024

Glisten International Academy

High School Diploma Sep 2017 - Nov 2020

Licenses & Certifications

- Microsoft Office Specialist: Microsoft Office 2016 PowerPoint Microsoft wbcnR-FMpS
- Microsoft Office Specialist: Microsoft Office 2016 Excel Microsoft dHRK-XVHb
- Microsoft Office Specialist: Microsoft Office 2016 Word Microsoft wAa2A-22XH
- Microsoft Office Specialist: Microsoft Office 2019 Word Associate Microsoft ecMW-4wTq
- Spython Core Sololearn Certificate #1073-12752775
- SHTML Fundamentals course Sololearn Certificate #1014-12752775
- Spython for Beginners Course Sololearn Certificate #1157-12752775
- **Java** Sololearn Certificate 12752775-1068
- Get Started with Figma Coursera
 GF7P2NUC538Y
- Build Mobile App with Google Sheets on Glide Coursera KM8FAEARBRVE
- Microsoft Office Specialist: Microsoft Office 2013 Word Microsoft DLEy-4TYH
- Work with Components in Figma Coursera

DW7F2CXFTL3H

Car Transport App in Figma - Coursera DN69CNALWMTD

Cybersecurity Fundamentals - IBM

c5b9d4ca-c1fa-4e37-a9d3-5b0f27b35c70

Skills

Beta Testing • Startups • Innovation Development • Realization • Bootstrap (Framework) • Microsoft Outlook • IT Hardware Support • Software Support • User support • Figma (Software)

Honors & Awards

- 21st Century Added Value Skill Training Glisten International Academy Sep 2020
- DIGITAL & ENTERPRISING PERSONS OF THE YEAR Glisten International Academy
 Sep 2020